Mezu Orizu



duzioristo@gmail.com



+23409090202853



linkedin.com/in/mezu-orizu-a50612230



https://mezuo.netlify.app/

Summary

I am a Full-stack web developer with several years of experience building websites and web applications. I specialize in PHP and JavaScript, I have professional experience working with Laravel and ReactJs. I also have experience developing range of web applications for start-up and small to enterprise level web applications.

Core skills and strengths:

FRONTEND Development:

✓ Html, CSS and JavaScript.

Frameworks:

✓ ReactJs, AlpineJs, TailwindCss, MaterialUI and Bootstrap.

BACKEND Development:

✓ PHP8

Frameworks:

✓Laravel.

Servers:

✓ WAMP (Windows, Apache, MySQL, PHP8),

√LARAGON

✓XAMPP(cross-platform, Apache, MySQL, PHP and Perl,)

Databases:

✓MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite.

RESTAPI:

- ✓ Laravel Passport(Oauth2 Authentication) and Laravel Sanctum,
- ✓ Payment gateway integration (Paystack , Stripe, PayPal),
- ✓ Mailing API (Sendpulse, Sendinblue),
- ✓ REST API development and integration.

Please contact me to discuss your requirements to determine how I can utilize my skills to help you...

Experience



Fullstack developer

Oristouniversal

Apr 2021 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

I was tasked to create a web app to advertise the companies chemical products and connect them with their customers using Sendinblue email service and Whatsapp API in contact form and page respectively. As the only developer involved in the project.

- I built the web application using Laravel blade, Laravel, Tailwindcss and Alpinejs.
- I hosted the web application using shared hosting and was in charge of managing ssh interactions.

Web Developer

Opiofiber

Feb 2019 - Dec 2019 (11 months)

I created the website to help advertise the companies manufactured products.

- I created the website using html, css and jquery.
- I hosted the website on garantor using shared hosting services.

Web Developer

Soughtoutroofing

Mar 2018 - Nov 2018 (9 months)

I created the website to help advertise the companies manufactured products.

- I created the website using html, css and jquery.
- I hosted the website on garantor using shared hosting services.

Education



Babcock University, Ilishan-Remo, Nigeria

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science 2014 - 2019

Skills

React.js • Bootstrap • AlpineJs • Tailwind CSS • JavaScript • Laravel • PHP • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • API Development